[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[hums]
[哼哼]
Let's go!
Come on!
我们走吧！
快点！
Huh?
啊？
Hey, what's the hold up
in there?
嘿，有什么好坚持的
在那里？
You're acting like you've never
cooked a Krabby Patty before.
你的表现就像你从未有过一样
之前煮过蟹肉饼。
[bell rings]
- Yeah, Dad, that's because
[铃声响起]
- 是的，爸爸，那是因为
I never have cooked
a Krabby Patty before.
我从来没有煮过饭
之前有一个蟹肉饼。
Why are you making me do this?
你为什么要让我这么做？
Because today is bring...
因为今天带来的是...
I mean, put your daughter
to work day.
我的意思是，把你的女儿
到工作日。
Besides, SpongeBob is busy deep
cleaning the barrel chairs.
此外，海绵宝宝很忙
清洁桶椅。
[hums]
[哼哼]
Uh, do you mind?
呃，你介意吗？
Oh, no, not at all.
哦，不，一点也不。
[whistles]
- [groans]
[口哨声]
- [呻吟]
Here's your food or whatever.
这是你的食物或者其他什么。
Oh, hi, SpongeBob.
- Hi, Pearl.
哦，嗨，海绵宝宝。
- 嗨，珍珠。
Isn't this just
the best job ever?
这不就是
有史以来最好的工作？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[gasps]
Hmm.
[喘气]
嗯。
- How do, SpongeBob!
- [screams]
- 怎么办，海绵宝宝！
- [尖叫]
Narlene.
纳琳。
Hey, where's your brother,
Nobby?
嘿，你弟弟在哪儿
诺比？
[groans]
[呻吟]
Ma'am.
女士。
Me and Nobby was just
on our way to the big city,
我和诺比只是
在我们去大城市的路上，
so we thought we'd take you up
所以我们想带你上去
on your offer
to show us the sights.
根据您的报价
向我们展示景点。
Ooh, I'd love to.
哦，我很愿意。
We can say hi
to my favorite fire hydrant
我们可以打个招呼
到我最喜欢的消防栓
and then we can see the old man
that feeds the clams
然后我们就可以看到老人了
喂蛤蜊的
and then... no.
然后...不。
I can't abandon
these lovely people.
我不能放弃
这些可爱的人。
all: [chewing and burping]
全部：[咀嚼和打嗝]
Ooh, then why don't
I show you around the big city?
哦，那为什么不呢
我带你参观大城市？
I don't care about these people.
我不关心这些人。
Little Pearly's gonna
take us on an adventure?
小珍珠会
带我们去冒险？
Hot dippity!
热辣辣的！
Anything to get out
of this place.
什么都可以出去
这个地方的。
It'll be a whale's day out.
这将是鲸鱼的一天。
[grunts]
Hard day's work.
[咕哝]
辛苦了一天。
[grunts]
- [groans]
[咕哝]
- [呻吟]
Nobby says he's fixing to stay
诺比说他决定留下来
and help SpongeBob
with the hungry folk.
并帮助海绵宝宝
与饥饿的人们一起。
So, Pearl, looks like
we got ourselves a deal.
所以，珍珠，看起来像
我们达成了协议。
[hocks, spits]
[飞节，吐口水]
- Okay.
- This'll be great.
- 好的。
- 这会很棒的。
Two whale gals reconnoitering
the big city together.
两只鲸鱼女孩在侦察
大城市在一起。
If we want to do that
"noitering" thing in the city,
如果我们想这么做
城市里的“闹事”，
I'll need an advance
on my allowance.
我需要预付款
在我的津贴上。
Oh, Daddy!
哦，爸爸！
[groans]
All right, here you go.
[呻吟]
好吧，给你。
Ugh, Dad, we can't have
a whale's day out
呃，爸爸，我们不能
鲸鱼出游的一天
with your balsa wood card.
用您的轻木卡。
We need the diamond unlimited!
我们需要无限的钻石！
My diamond.
我的钻石。
[horn honks]
- I never took a Scuber before,
[喇叭鸣响]
- 我以前从未拿过Scuber，
but it sure is
mighty convenient.
但确实如此
非常方便。
'Preciate the lift.
[grunts]
'珍惜电梯。
[咕哝]
Huh?
啊？
I'll be!
我会的！
These city streets is paved
with chewing candy.
这些城市街道已铺好
与咀嚼糖。
[grunts]
I'm saving you as a souvenir.
[咕哝]
我把你留作纪念。
Ah.
啊。
Ah!
啊!
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Mm.
毫米。
Ah!
Tasty.
啊!
可口。
Uh, the city also has
呃，这个城市也有
a lot of things in it
that aren't gross.
里面有很多东西
这并不恶心。
Really?
真的吗？
Oh,
like these fancy shacks here?
哦，
喜欢这里这些别致的小屋吗？
Yeah, these are skyscrapers.
是的，这些是摩天大楼。
And that?
那呢？
That's public transportation.
那是公共交通。
Ow.
噢。
[jackhammer rattling]
- What's he doing?
[手提钻嘎嘎作响]
- 他在做什么？
Street construction!
街道建设！
[laughs]
[笑]
[groans]
Ooh.
[呻吟]
哦。
Why, it's like
walking through a TV show.
为什么，就像
走过电视节目。
Phew.
Ah.
唷。
啊。
[timer beeping]
Huh?
[定时器蜂鸣声]
啊？
Uh-oh, the fries.
If only I could reach them.
呃哦，薯条。
如果我能联系到他们就好了。
[yelping, grunting]
[尖叫，咕噜声]
Oh.
哦。
Wow. Thanks, Nobby.
哇。谢谢，诺比。
Now if only the condiments
were closer.
现在只要调味品
更接近了。
- [grunts] Here you go.
- Ah.
- [咕哝]给你。
- 啊。
- [babbling]
- [laughs]
- [胡言乱语]
- [笑]
Too bad the bun rack is
on the other side of the room.
可惜面包架是
在房间的另一边。
Oh, yeah!
This is what I call fast food!
哦，是啊！
这就是我所说的快餐！
This is my favorite
department store
这是我最喜欢的
and, like,
the heart of the big city.
并且，就像，
Upturn's.
回升的。
[energetic music]
[充满活力的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Whoa.
哇哦。
Huh?
啊？
Ooh!
哦！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
These here automatic doors
sure is frilly,
这里的这些自动门
当然是褶边，
but we hill folk do things
a little more polite-like.
但我们山民做事
更有礼貌一点。
[grunts]
Right this way, sir.
[咕哝]
这边走，先生。
[groans]
[呻吟]
Excuse me!
打扰一下！
What do you think you're doing?
你认为你在做什么？
Uh, holding the door.
Here, you try.
呃，扶着门。
在这里，你试试。
- [groans]
- Narlene, that's Lady Upturn.
- [呻吟]
- 纳琳，那是Upturn女士。
[groans, huffs]
[呻吟，怒气]
[laughs]
I'm so sorry.
[笑]
我很抱歉。
She's new in town,
but we'll be good shoppers.
她刚进城，
但我们会成为好的购物者。
I swear.
- Hmm, yes.
我发誓。
- 嗯，是的。
All right, carry on,
my little consumerists.
好吧，继续，
我的小消费主义者。
But here at Upturn's,
we take shopping seriously.
但在Upturn's这里，
我们认真对待购物。
both: Okay.
两人：好的。
Welcome to
the perfume department.
欢迎来到
香水部。
[sweeping music]
[席卷音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[coughs and sneezes]
[咳嗽和打喷嚏]
Phew-wee!
唷！
I think something
done died up in here.
我觉得有件事
完成死在这里。
Died and went to heaven!
死后去了天堂！
Yeah!
[laughing]
是的！
[笑]
[sighs]
[叹气]
Ambergris.
[laughs]
龙涎香。
[笑]
I... [chokes]
我……[窒息]
[yelping]
[尖叫]
Why, you!
为什么，你！
Yes?
是的？
What's your problem?
你有什么问题吗？
I've got a cleanup on aisle you.
我已经帮你清理过道了。
Perhaps another sample spritz?
也许还有一个样品喷雾？
Sorry, but I ain't too
'ticular about that stench.
抱歉，但我也不是
特别是那种恶臭。
Really.
真的。
Besides, I carry my own
signature stink.
除此之外，我还带着自己的
签名臭。
- Huh?
- Toadstool tang.
- 啊？
- 毒菌汤。
[laughs]
Wa-hoo!
[笑]
哇呼！
My nose!
我的鼻子！
The horrible stench!
可怕的恶臭！
- [coughs]
- [groans]
- [咳嗽]
- [呻吟]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
Come on, we better cheese it!
来吧，我们最好干酪了！
What do you think
about this cool dress?
你觉得怎么样
关于这件很酷的衣服？
I don't know.
It's kind of constricting.
我不知道。
这有点收缩。
both: [laughs]
两人：[笑]
Attention, Upturn's shoppers.
Upturn 的购物者请注意。
There's a sale
in the shoe department.
有促销活动
在鞋类部门。
Tenth floor.
- [gasps] Come on!
十楼。
- [喘气]来吧！
Whoa!
哇！
[elevator dinging]
[电梯叮叮声]
Whoa.
[elevator dings]
哇哦。
[电梯叮叮声]
No way.
So many shoes!
决不。
这么多鞋子！
[laughs]
[笑]
Huh?
啊？
[gasps]
[喘气]
[sighs]
[叹气]
- [gasps]
- [laughs]
- [喘气]
- [笑]
Uh, no offense, Pearly girl,
呃，无意冒犯，珍珠女孩，
but my feet
don't cotton much to shoes.
但我的脚
鞋子上不要涂太多棉。
As the saying goes,
there's a tiny shoe
俗话说，
有一只小鞋
for every giant foot.
- Whoa!
对于每一个巨大的脚。
- 哇！
May I?
我可以？
Well, if the shoe fits.
好吧，如果鞋子合脚的话。
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
[growling]
[咆哮]
You slaughtered my stiletto!
你杀了我的高跟鞋！
Sorry.
I told you.
对不起。
我告诉你了。
Wait a minute.
I know you two.
等一下。
我认识你们两个。
You're those hooligans!
你们就是那些流氓！
It's those wily whales.
就是那些狡猾的鲸鱼。
Code red!
红色代码！
[alarm blaring]
[警报声]
[elevator dings]
both: [grunting]
[电梯叮叮声]
两人：[咕哝]
[laughs and grunts]
[笑声和咕哝声]
[soldiers grunting]
[士兵咕哝]
- Hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut!
- Ha!
- 小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋！
- 哈！
Hut, hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut.
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Ah!
啊!
Lady Upturn!
Sorry.
女士逆袭！
对不起。
Narlene and I
were just having some fun.
纳琳和我
我们只是玩得开心。
Fun?
乐趣？
Shopping is
not supposed to be fun.
购物是
不应该很有趣。
Fortunately for me,
对我来说幸运的是，
you'll never
be shopping here again!
你永远不会
再次来这里购物！
But I had
the diamond unlimited card.
但我有
钻石无限卡。
[cries]
[哭声]
all: Hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut, hut.
全部： 小屋，小屋，小屋，
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋。
- Come on, let's get.
- Ah!
- 来吧，我们开始吧。
- 啊！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[mellow music playing]
[柔和的音乐播放]
[elevator dings]
both: [panting]
[电梯叮叮声]
两人：[气喘吁吁]
Whoa!
[elevator dings]
哇！
[电梯叮叮声]
all: Hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut.
全部： 小屋，小屋，小屋，
小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋。
You, young ladies,
do not belong here,
你们，年轻的女士们，
不属于这里，
especially her.
尤其是她。
Huh?
啊？
So what if my friend
doesn't do things
那如果我的朋友
不做事
the way city people do?
城里人怎么做？
At least she's not
a stuck-up snob like you.
至少她不是
像你这样自以为是的势利小人
- Oh!
- Besides.
- 哦！
- 除了。
- Mm.
- we cetacean sisters
- 毫米。
- 我们鲸类姐妹
always stick together.
永远粘在一起。
[yelps, grunts]
[尖叫声，咕噜声]
Ah! Ah.
啊!啊。
[grunts, heaves]
[咕哝声，起伏]
[all grunt]
[全都咕哝]
- Oh!
- [grunting]
- 哦！
- [咕哝]
- Yee-haw!
- Hey!
- 哎呀！
- 嘿！
[blowing whistle]
[吹口哨]
Ha-ha, whoa.
哈哈，哇。
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[laughs]
[笑]
[screams]
all: Hut, hut, hut, hut.
[尖叫声]
全部：小屋，小屋，小屋，小屋。
Diamond unlimited!
钻石无限！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[playful music]
[有趣的音乐]
I've got it.
我明白了。
♪ ♪
♪♪
both: [groans]
两人：[呻吟]
Huh? Ah!
- [yelps]
啊？啊!
- [尖叫声]
[babbling]
[胡说]
My bad.
我的不好。
[whistles]
[口哨声]
- [yells]
- Aw!
- [大喊]
- 噢！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Looks like
they worked you like a horse.
看起来像
他们像马一样让你工作。
- Yeah.
- Aw.
- 是的。
- 噢。
Oh.
- [whinnies]
哦。
- [嘶嘶声]
both: [laughs]
两人：[笑]
Thanks for
the whale's day out, Pearl,
谢谢
鲸鱼外出的一天，珍珠，
but the big city's
more trouble than it's worth.
但大城市的
麻烦多于其价值。
Next time, you're coming
to the countryside.
下次你也来
到乡下。
- [laughs]
- Yeah, let's do that sometime.
- [笑]
- 是的，我们找个时间这样做吧。
Yee-haw!
[laughs]
呀呀！
[笑]
Pearl, what's the deal with
all these charges at Upturn's?
珍珠，这是怎么回事
Upturn 的所有这些费用？
Why wait?
为什么要等？
Let's go to the countryside
right now.
我们去乡村吧
现在。
[upbeat western music]
[欢快的西方音乐]
Goodbye, Daddy!
See you real soon.
再见，爸爸！
很快就能见到你了。
- Sooner than you think!
- [screams]
- 比你想象的要早！
- [尖叫]
Wait, wait!
等等，等等！
Where do you think you're going?
你认为你要去哪里？
You can't go away now!
你现在不能走！
Hello?
Anybody there?
你好？
有人在吗？